rulers of the seven emirates. They meet
together they decide to make something
good for the nation and it's kind of
seven small countries united to one
country and everyone was looking for the
good for the people not for any personal
benefit and that's what really make the
union and the country successful cuz
there's no really competition. Everyone
is competing only how to serve people.
>> So he's the guy why Dubai is so
futuristic.
>> In our study we found out there is at
least 2 million fake academic
certificate in US every year in
circulation. 2 million
>> 2 million in circulation every year and
there is a 300 non-existing fake
universities and institute in UK issuing
certificate and none of them are even in
in UK land and give you like Harvard
Stanford MIT certificate without even
being there
>> stop applicants they're like trust me
bro I went to Harvard now you kind of
have to prove it to me
>> believe me they soon will remove that
from the lickin and their website maybe
the only certificate that maybe could be
gen is the marriage certificate because
it's not forever it's not immutable
maybe if we have a lot of supporter from
the woman around the world maybe we'll
put it immutable so it will be once and
no no divorce is allowed after issuing
it
>> so in a world where [music] information
is almost going to be free AI is so
powerful what is valuable like right now
I'm valuable because I can get give you
the correct answer really [music] fast
or I am a great employee because I can
give you the right direction really fast
but with AI these are not important
anymore
in Dubai and I'm so honored to be joined
by Dr. Muhammad Alanmary. He is, listen
to this, he is the chairman of a UAE AI
and blockchain association. So he's the
guy why Dubai is so futuristic.
>> Well, that's uh too big for me.
[laughter] Uh well uh UAE and Dubai
actually has been starting into
innovation into process uh transactions
government services long time ago and um
this what make Dubai very uh magnet to
people starting from tourism. People
start resident here and also investors
as well. they move and transfer their
work and businesses here and establish
reallocate in Dubai uh and leaving very
um advanced communities like in Europe
and US and some also some Asia part and
come here that shows that how the
government care about the people people
uh feeling comfortable people feeling
safe and having everything uh they need
fingertip away from them use using
mobile app fully integrated with
hundreds if not thousands of surfaces.
Uh uh today I hardly remember uh
government transaction that need
paperwork or need my signature or even
need me to go to that government entity
to sign or to meet someone. We do
everything online and uh uh the funny
things which has I I really even I'm I
was a very technological person uh
thought that the court I mean the
hearing in the court and this the you
know opponents sitting together fighting
in in the front of the judge with the
lawyers this is the last thing that can
be uh automated and digitized and become
online. Now we have it online in uh in
UAE uh like since 5 years ago. Yeah.
Since uh co started they moved
everything online the hearing the whole
court uh sessions online and since then
they still doing online. So no one need
really to go to the to the court by
himself and wait for hours to uh to
fight or to defend themselves. They can
do this at home. Uh especially for
female or like uh mothers they they
they're looking for uh for their rights
or for the kids. Imagine to to go there
to leave their family to to leave her
work to go there and sit for hours. Now
the court comes to you at home. Uh so
imagine how this convenient um to
everyone.
>> It is crazy because I landed two days
ago and I booked a massage right away
just on an app and the lady came right
away. I'm like this is heaven. This is
so amazing.
>> Yeah, that's true. I mean think of
anything comes in your mind that you may
need. Uh with a little search you will
find hundreds if not thousands service
provider available. Either they come to
you or they if it is something can
offered online uh they do online and if
there's something they can deliver at
home they will deliver at home.
>> There is something about Dubai. Every
time I come, I feel like people are just
very encouraged to take risk. Like you
just go out and try um just create. But
that is very different from a lot of
developed countries. People tend to be
more conservative. They want to preserve
what they have.
>> What is it in the blood of the Amiradis?
>> Well, this is the back to the DNA of the
government.
uh our government fundamental is to
enable everyone to suggest ideas and
also innovate and then they will look at
this uh suggestions and see if it will
really help the people make them life
easier. It increase our efficiency at
work especially at government then they
going to adopt it and again adop
adopting a new technology or early stage
surfaces could be kind of risky or could
work or doesn't work. That's why the
government especially the prime minister
and the cabinet they create something
called um uh policy uh sandbox.
>> So all these ideas will be tested in a
temporary environment for a temporary
period of time.
>> If it we they see it works then they're
going to uh make it a a regular surfaces
and adopt it. If it doesn't work we are
not losing anything. We are trying
something new. I think this flexibility
uh and dynamic into uh for policy makers
uh will really that makes us uh very
fast into uh uh updating and also u uh
inventing a new new surfaces for our
people and our nation and that's what
make people love Dubai and love UAE as
well.
>> Do you think it's the education here
that is a little different from
everywhere else? Well, the education
definitely play a big role especially
for the new generation. Now we have uh
since like the Bree school and the older
school they are aware of all the
technology available. So they they use
it, they test it and they become um um
uh familiar with and now they move to
also to the to the young generation
which is like in from 20 to 30 and then
they also have a programs to educate and
where people from 40 plus to 60 and 70
and es especially in the time of the
covid we had it five years ago it really
accelerate the the the adoption of
technology especially with the with the
elder people and since then they they
they start to do everything um online
from their mobile. I have a a license
company and then I have a rent house and
then I uh the landlord called me and say
we need to to renew the uh the tenants
uh and the contract so you can u uh
apply or uh renew your license. said
okay yes uh can we meet tomorrow and say
no you don't need to come to me and he's
imagine he's about 70 plus and he say no
no no just just initiate the the the
request from your um uh we have
application called UAE pass which is
like like the gateway for u um
integrated services and say initiated I
receive a notification I will approve
and uh and uh that's it will be done
there contract will be renewed between
the tenant and leaves and they say this
was first time to me because I never
tried this before but imagine 70 plus
years uh immirati guy he is he's aware
he's using it he's he's okay with it and
he's even um uh you know teaching us I
think this is how smart government
should work in the base of the industry
or even competing to be even faster
>> for people that has not been to the UAE
I think they have this stereotype of oh
it's just such a rich place but I don't
think people realize how advanced it is
and it's from a government's level let
me give you an example um a 70 plus year
old in let's say east Asia they have
given up on learning because their life
has been good right so it's okay to just
use paper money transaction I don't want
to learn something that is digital and
could be risky because there could be
scam blah blah blah and the mentality
here is just very different and I would
love for you to maybe dive in a little
bit about the history of Dubai because
it used to be a desert.
>> Yeah,
>> definitely. That's takes us back to the
founders of uh the country uh the rulers
of u the seven emirates. They meet
together they they decide to make
something uh for good for the the the
nation and the population. And it it's
it's kind of seven small countries
united into one uh one country and
everyone was uh uh looking for the
people the good for the people not for
any any personal uh benefit and that's
what really make the union and the
country successful because there is no
really competition and everyone is
looking competing only for this how to
serve people and uh and the only way is
to make this country as I said it is in
the desert uh um uh appealing and
something attractive to people is having
like the best uh quality of life and
also high standard of surfaces that
makes everybody's life easier. So when
they go compare like what they are
having here with the with their uh
countries, they will see the difference
and they say okay they will have the now
some uh kind of um uh reason why they
should decide to move here and bring
their uh family and kids to be raised as
well here. Even it is like uh 40 plus
and sometimes 50 plus degrees in the
summer but still uh we have uh other
ways to um overcome these kind of
challenges. uh now with the some uh
climate change we are going to more uh
cold and cool um uh summers as well than
uh than before. So um I I think from
this uh perspective um the the
government wants everyone to uh to try
the surfaces first and uh it comes
gradually by allowing two options either
with a cash money or digital money like
using Visa. people will see which is
easier for them and by time they start
to move and shift into the a new uh
digital or new uh more electronic way
having paper uh transaction with like 30
40 pages uh and then you have to go to
different units and department to get
the stamp proof uh checks and so on
still it's not efficient it's can be
also uh manipulated can be um uh like
paper can be lost and then you have to
start over comparing to something
digital like from one Even though you
have information pop up from different
databases, from different departments
and units, they are totally separate.
They all share the same purpose to make
uh one window uh for the customer to
deal with uh filling the minimum
information and uh and that's it. then
he can get uh approved and processed
with the system and also the government
strategy that launches from time to time
like paperless environment uh by 2030. I
think we reached even like seven years
before we we reached this environment
almost there. So it's very minimum
surfaces that require papers but the
rest are all totally digital. So um I
think if we uh this way with with a lots
of um uh focus uh encouragement and also
enabler industry um partners as well to
subsidize some of the services to them
that really help as well to u u make it
faster to to happen since uh COVID 19
most of us did not since today did not
carry any uh cash money or fiat money.
Uh we don't we we we have money in the
bank but we didn't don't use the card to
withdraw money from from the bank. Uh I
I didn't see my booket honestly. I don't
have it since 2020.
>> That's amazing.
>> Yeah. I I never I don't need it. So
everything I do electronically I do bank
transaction using uh online banking.
Even I have the I don't even take the
cards because I don't have to go to the
ATM. The the ATM card are in my mobile.
And also now with regulating the web3
services and also crypto and blockchain
uh based project as well. We can also do
uh money transfer. We can do online
trading uh also using our uh wallets on
mobiles or on computer and that's it.
Fore
speaking.
Can you tell me a joke?
>> Why did the tomato turn red?
>> Because the tomato is shy.
Speech analyzer.
Fore.
May I ask you? So that sounds like a lot
of things are going to be on blockchain
because you want a system that can work
everywhere
and let's talk about money. Is UAE going
to start a stable coin? You think
>> that's a standing project since a few
years and I think still under
development. Um um maybe postponed a
little bit because of the logistics but
I'm sure it's it's going to happen very
soon. uh there's already uh signed
between the uh stakeholders like central
bank um other authorities and also uh
digital asset authorities to do so and
also there is signed with the Saudi
government as well to have a a a kind of
digital currencies like tying the
durhams with the Saudi real as well. So
I think it's not only new, it will
become in the region where we don't
really need um um the normal currencies
anymore and we can use the digital uh
currencies which is really a fourth
dimension into the um normal
conventional money transaction into
banks. First of all will be very fast,
super fast. It will inate a lot of
hypocrisies and uh you know bank
transactions u u u it will have more
control into the compliance and anti-
money money laundereries. Uh also you
can also as a user I will know exactly
and detailed um uh expense statement
about how much I spend my money during
on monthly basis and then how I can
utilize my expenses and and and I can
maybe uh focus in more investment than
expenses and so on. So it will really
enable you to do a lot of things that is
it wasn't available on the current
system uh using the normal banking.
>> Two questions there. A person that is
not familiar with stablecoin will be
like that is scary. If I can see all my
transactions does that mean other people
can? That is the first question. And the
second is what happens to those
countries that are like we don't want to
have our own stable coin.
>> Well there the first message is for the
user who are concerned about the
privacy. First of all, in the current
system uh I mean if you have your bank
your your money in the bank and uh your
source of funding uh and income you have
to disclose it to your uh government
anyway. So they they are they know what
what is there and from where you get
your bank statement with full incomes
and expenses from the bank. So the bank
knows and the banks share it with with
authorities whenever it's needed or
there's anything suspicious. So in in
terms of privacy uh moving into stable
coins or any kind of digital currencies
will be the same. The second uh uh thing
in this uh point is that it will be even
more secure because you will have
control by you know the private key to
get to grant access to any third party
to share or not share and being having
like the trans the data onto the
blockchain doesn't mean it will become
totally public. It will be encrypted
anyway. So the data will be there people
they saw there is a block hasing data
but it's like you know Pandora box they
don't know what is inside unless you
have the key for that. So terms of
security it would be secure. The second
thing as in the decentralized um uh uh
environment like in like public ledger
or blockchain first of all it will be
secure it will be encrypted and it will
be decentralized. So if there is one
site or server pro uh server data center
has been fallen or disconnected the
others will will tell that yes this
person has this kind of amount of money.
So you are more safer uh environment.
The second message is for the
government. Um for for the government u
um they been suffering a lot into uh
controlling the cash flow within the
country. Huge amount of money are within
the country. they cannot see and they
are struggling to find out and to
control or to seize. Now when they go to
the CBDC's
they will have uh more uh oversee about
this uh money especially the big amounts
of money where it goes if it is legal so
that is okay for them and also for the
the for the the person or the uh money
holder. If it is not okay then they
should take an action to for the sake of
the environment the s of the community
and also for the the people. So I think
it will be more um not control it will
be more safe environment uh for the
government and also uh more privacy and
control in hand of the uh customers as
well. Earlier you mentioned CBDC and I
think um in the US Trump of course he
said he is not for CBDC and they are
using Genius Act as a way to promote the
US Treasurybacked
uh USC USDC
and all the regulated stable coins. Um I
think different regions have their own
personalities. Some are more suitable
for U uh CBDC's some are more free
flowing stables. How do you see the
difference between these two?
>> Well, that depends from um uh country to
country as everyone has a different
objective why they want to do so. Some
of them they want to do like the minimum
because they want to be um uh you know
in line with the latest technology
because the people um since the the the
Bitcoin comes out they become ahead of
the government in terms of adopting
digital assets and transaction and do
peer-to-peer transactions without any
third party and they are okay with that.
So some government they feel they are
behind and they should do at least
something in this uh or maybe find a reg
uh you know regulatory framework as well
to people to work or uh if there's any
kind of uh criminal acts they should
also interfere but uh again uh for the
US uh the problem is that every time we
have a change in the in the objectives
and they have a different uh plans as
well so it's it will be hard to see
where they are going but what I'm what
I'm I'm see here they are trying to find
uh solution for allowing people to deal
because there's a lot of pressure from
the people in US to uh work in a legal
uh uh frame into the uh digital assets
and the second thing is that their depth
which is increasing massively and I
think they're trying to find an exit
from that using the digital uh
currencies or stable coins in different
ways. how they gonna do it unless they
they started uh we are not sure because
we we're seeing we're hearing different
announcement from time to time acts and
plans but which one will really work uh
we don't know uh you know sometimes
government announce something they don't
really uh do it now or they postpone it
uh later or maybe they see some
challenge and difficulties but I think
if they going to do that they will
really open up for every uh government
especially Europe to follow and to do to
do the same and then transaction and
settlement between central banks around
the world will be much easier much
efficient and less costly in comparing
to the swift or wide transfer and this
kind of tools.
>> So to to the earlier question
governments that are not working on the
stable coins they're just going to be
left behind.
>> Definitely. Yeah,
>> definitely. At least they should uh
attest it in uh uh like they have a test
environment because if everybody uh like
government they they moved to this new
system and they are left behind. They
has still like they they will have a
technology gap where they they should
start something experiment see the the
the pros and cons and advantage
disadvantages they have to go through
this experiment they cannot import
technology and then they can start. So
uh if they don't start yet and have like
a this environment or maybe sandbox uh
uh to to try they will they will create
this gap by themselves and they will be
left behind
>> off camera we were talking about how UAE
came up with a framework that a lot of
governments follow. Can you tell us more
about that? The U government actually uh
as I said since 2018 they have
established the the white paper and guid
guidelines of uh of digital asset and
bitcoin and later on then they have uh
we have launched they have launched a
Dubai uh blockchain strategy and then
the Dubai virtual assets uh regulatory
uh uh authority and then Abu Dhabi has
also
ADGM also as a regulator for the the
market and now They open up a a license
framework for exchanges to operate for
in in UAE with the different levels and
they have to uh really uh go through the
process and as well until they get a
full operational license and some of
them are already get got like Binance
and others. They become um now uh free
and legal to work and operate here. Uh
and now this um um creates um a a paneer
and uh opportunity uh and uh testing
environment for uh with a rich
information for other governments who
want to come and do the same. They don't
have to start with the from zero. They
can come here and see our experience how
we did it, how we deal with it. And
recently, just a couple of days, our
central bank uh in UAE has uh um uh uh
sent a memo to all operational uh
exchanges here in in a in a web3 and
cryptocurrencies to ensure they are
complied with the AM act uh uh and also
ensure that all transaction happening on
their platform are legal at least here
in the UAE. So this is uh something
really shows that how we serious about
the adopting technology and also serious
about making the environment clean and
full compliance.
>> We are very used to hearing blockchain
and finance together because of crypto
all these exchanges being very popular.
But what else in what other areas are
you seeing real adoption? Well, there
are uh so many areas actually uh finance
is become like a big entity that's uh uh
because of like the cryptocurrencies and
everyone we we know the market but still
we have like the health care sector uh
the education for example in the
healthcare center sector for example the
patient records patient medical record
lab results to be also on the on the
blockchain and as I said in
decentralized environment but also very
secured and encrypted. So whenever he
goes and traveling around the world they
can be easily being accessed and it
cannot be lost as well. And imagine also
for this genetic disease and genetic
history and DNA maps for for the
generation can also be in this in the on
the blockchain and then we can also have
the genetic map of population and then
we can use that to massively reduce the
um uh the genetic diseases from the
newborns for the education uh sector.
For example, it can be used uh for
example for the uh issuing the
certificate of the uh student into the
blockchain and then they can uh using
only one link on a public uh key keys
they can share it with any employer they
are applying and then they can verify
their certificate easily without any any
need to being stamped from the ministry
of education uh and the the embassy of
US if they are going to US this is you
know it's insane it's in in Our study we
we we we count at least in average six
different stamps and entities you need
to verify one one certificate. Why? If
it is from day one issued on the
blockchain in the which is a mutable
database uh data are there forever
cannot be manipulated or changed and
also it is saved in a decentralized
environment distributed with so many
nodes around the world. So no one that
uh it will be lost completely and that's
it. It's uh it's verified from the day
it's issued. No need for any extra
stamps.
>> So So you're talking about every
university in the world eventually will
be on the datab base.
>> Definitely. We already received many um
requests to join the platform. We told
them it's still in the in the in the
testing environment and uh we will be
happy to everyone allowed to join. I
love that because a lot of people job
applicants, they're like, "Trust me,
bro. I went to Harvard. Now you kind of
have to prove it to me."
>> Believe me, they soon will will remove
that from their lick in and their
website, which is very very important,
especially people working in the medical
field, you know, medical doctors,
surgeons, uh maybe civil engineers,
building towers and they have a fake ID
or fake certificate.
>> Yeah. And again we can apply that for
any different types also certificate
like birth certificate for example birth
certificate can really uh result into
nationality of that country then also
you can for example if you want to many
like make your age smaller so you fake
you want to change your name
>> younger
>> yeah you can be or all elder depends
what purpose you are doing that this
illegal things and maybe you can also
change your name change your mother name
and you can do a lot of
that is illegal. So it is kind of uh
immutable certificate that issued once
with the data that shouldn't be changed
uh by time. Maybe the only certificate
that uh uh should be maybe could be
changed is the marriage certificate
because it's not forever. It's not
immutable. Okay. [laughter] But maybe if
we have a lot of supporter uh from the
the woman around the world, maybe we'll
put it immutable. So it will be once and
no divorce is allowed after issuing it.
So this is one one thing I mean imagine
adding a new child if you have a fake uh
birth certificate and fake marriage
certificate as well. You can add child
that not by your own and there are a lot
of uh you know consequences that can
happen on fake IDs. uh in our study we
have found out there is at least two
million fake uh academic certificate in
US every year in circulation
>> for maybe for alcohol consumption
>> well no I mean academic certificate so
they applying for job they they are
>> 2 million
>> 2 million in circulation every year and
there is a 300 uh non-existing uh fake
uh universities and institute in UK
issuing certificate and none of them are
even in in UK K land. So they are some
operating somewhere where around the
world and give you like Harvard,
Stanford, MIT certificate uh without
even being there. So it's a huge uh it's
a big uh issues. We're talking about
blockchain, but also your association
includes AI as well. And for a lot of
people, AI and blockchain seems like two
different topics, but we have AI agents
and we imagine that they're going to do
transactions without us even pressing
confirm on their own in the future. Like
AI agents doing services for each other
and stuff. What else can you help us
imagine the world would look like? Well,
first of all, the the association of
blockchain AI um exists because we think
that both technologies are emerging.
>> Mhm.
>> Both uh they need each others. I was in
earlier in today in my in my panel
speech I was explaining uh the the the
uh the AI actually u is a great tool is
open up a lot a lot of opportunities for
everyone making life easy but it's also
violate the copyright and intellectual
property right of people because u
whatever you shared and the AI can uh
use it to uh for uh for the learning and
extract and rephrase it as a fresh
document or text and provide right to
you and then you can claim you are the
owner of this which is in fact not. And
so using the blockchain now it can solve
this issue because whatever original
authentic word can be um uh uh recorded
on the blockchain. So it will maintain
the intellectual property and ownership
of the original authors and so if the AI
is blended with the blockchain so it
will always refer to the owner and and
original authors of the uh of the novel
work. Can I can I say in the future
let's say if AI take your article and
maybe my thoughts then they'll pay us a
little bit of the whatever result that
we come up with.
>> Well actually you you just steal my mind
the the what or or you know jump into
the the project we are launching now. Um
u the project is is very similar to what
you are saying since we want we we want
to give the um the uh the moral right
for those who authored uh the work and
uh generated the work originally where
we we can also monetize uh their
contribution into the public knowledge
and sharing their knowhow with anything
you know when when you run an AI agent
and using to inquire data uh for users
um
that will be a a cost or they they call
it uh tokens used to uh to for every
inquiry. So if you if if you are paying
for the the platform AI platform for the
for your inquiries and these inquiries
is based on others people work they
should be rewarded. So now we are using
the blockchain AI now uh to uh
acknowledge and also to compensate those
who contributed with their uh knowledge
uh base and and knowhow with with the
with the rest of the world.
>> And the next question is a little more
philosophical. So in a world where
information is almost going to be free,
AI is so powerful. What is valuable?
like right now I'm valuable because I
can get give you the correct answer
really fast or I am a great employee
because I can give you the right you
know direction really fast but with AI
these are not important anymore. Well,
this is really the challenge for AI
right now is how to uh verify the data
is it accurate or not and we have seen
like in different occasions the AI has
given wrong uh data misconceptions and
misleading as well. Going back to the
model we explained we are trying to
involve a peer review uh which is a
human process into verifying what is AI
is consuming and is providing to others.
So if we manage to do that by the human
supervision because human supervision
learning data for AI then we we kind
control and making sure that these data
are authentic they are um also uh
validated at least and it will it will
be provided with people without uh you
know um wrong messages and so on. That's
why we we we we will start with with
professors and uh researchers in
universities and in academia to be
involved into providing the data and
these data are based on experiment is
not came from social media. So if we
have this kind of um verified data that
can be used to train our model.
>> So that will ensure that we can provide
the right information and the right data
for the for the people who are using the
our model as well. You're giving the
professors a lot of power. So let's say
the professor want people to believe
something and then he can actually
train the AI to believe that too.
>> Our goal is to to focus on the
scientific data. Scientific data will
will have yes will have working facts
and experiments and uh those who are
like say political opinion personal
opinion opinion on on life or lifestyle
won't be our focus because that is no
way to have uh all everyone agree on
something but whenever someone like for
discover something in um in the lab uh
in in my uh area I I show it to the
whole world they can they can also redo
it if if they reach the same uh result
then it become a fact no one they can uh
question that but in in in personal
opinion it it's it's different you know
everyone has a different opinion and and
I think we should keep the freedom of of
thinking and freedom of u opinion
>> do you really believe that I feel like
sometimes there are things there a
little too far
>> well it depends uh in what topic so I I
I I think as AI should stay away from
this one because he cannot impose his
opinion based on the data has was
trained by a group of people into the
other side of uh people or believers in
a different way. So let's focus on the
science science and science doesn't lie
as they used to say and and if there is
anything we can uh like two people uh in
the world can agree is something uh fact
and reality
>> you just sparked my curiosity. Okay. So,
right now if I ask the AI platforms
about a history fact, if I name it like
that, they'll give me the story. But
then in this scenario, yes, it is
biased. Everything is biased. So now
what? Like are we heading into a world
where AI is only supposed to tell you
let's say scientific fact instead of
telling you anything that involves
uh countries or emotions and Well, uh
look, currently the AI is uh give you
answers on everything. Yeah, exactly.
So, it never say I don't know even they
don't have the the the idea and uh
that's because we allow allow it to work
this way to find any source uh available
and extract data and provide you because
it's uh its goal is to provide you with
with all your queries. Now uh from where
uh it get this data is from a source. AI
has also now the capability to screen
all available sources and try to bring
you with different opinions say this
fact comes from this this source and
this fact come from this source. And
this is what I actually teach my student
whenever uh I encourage them to use the
AI uh not to uh to avoid it is to always
ask the AI in the inquiry about the
source provide the source and they they
should follow the link and see if it is
really available there or it is
different or it is like um a random
source because you know AI has some
issues uh right now in the accuracy of
data and that would make them to uh
always explore where this fact comes
they cannot take it and immediately
apply it. This is very common use by the
way. Everybody is doing this uh without
checking the source is remember the the
one the the the uh the platform you are
asking and inquiring is not a medical
doctor is a is a machine. machine is
trained on a certain data and if it is
not trained well it can really really
harm your health by providing uh a wrong
uh medical advice. Uh so uh so this is
how it should be. We shouldn't depend on
one source. We should go uh and bring
all thoughts all different sources and
and and the reader or the user has the
right to to choose wherever he think is
right.
>> You just mentioned you have a lot of
students. What do you advise them to do?
Like how do you survive this new era
that people are just so uncertain about?
I can be so good at math but AI is going
to be better. I can be so good at this
but AI can do better. What is the core
skill that I I should train myself to
do?
>> Well, um universities uh right now um
shouldn't um teach the student
everything. M
>> that is the the the classical model of
uh of of academic learning. Now they
should work uh depends more on self
learning including using using AI uh and
it helps helps a lot by the way and also
the assessment of the student uh
performance should also be changed
because uh we used to give uh as ana
academia used to give them uh homework
and we used to give them project to work
on and now it's apparently they just uh
ask the AI to to do it in a couple of
minutes and then they bring you the is
state-of-the-art well establish
structured report with graphics and data
and facts and and so on. So how should
should I give them full mark or should
give them uh uh half mark because of the
they use the AI? Well, the for me and
for I think for many other uh academics
uh there our objectives is that uh the
student has uh learned something and he
is he has creating and enrich his
knowhow uh database uh and and uh and
knowledge. So if that happens then it's
fine to use any tools. So what what what
happens that say okay this is the
assignment you do the report and then
you come to me and do pitching in the
front of the class. So everything I ask
and say okay can you explain can you
tell me where which part you are uh you
worked on explain to me in your own
language. So if it shows that he he
understand what he's saying and what
he's presenting then okay the for me
learning process is is okay and it's
done the the job. If he doesn't know
what he's talking about, it means that
he totally it will it will be apparently
uh clear and of course that this is how
we assess assist them. Plus we'll do a
lot of offline exams where we they they
they do we go back to the pen and pencil
as well. So we we to test their uh
understanding and their uh knowledge as
well. We use also the technologies and
uh improve ourself as well to u um you
know to improve the learning and
academic process as well.
>> I love that because I think a lot of
schools are so terrified that you know
students are just going to use AI but
like you said it is a tool and I love
your explanation about just be able to
say it out loud what you learn.
>> Yes.
>> Because that is literally what YouTubers
do. We we do a lot of research and then
we just say it out loud. And I think
that to me is the only way I know uh I
I've learned something
>> because if I've only like read an
article, it's not mine yet.
>> Exactly.
>> Thank you so much for your time.
>> This was beautiful. I think this episode
will be watched by a lot of people in
the government because people are
looking at UAE as this model when it
turn when it comes to tech and web 3 and
blockchain. So, thank you for what you
guys do.
>> Thank you, Bonnie. And uh I hope to
enjoy blockchain uh uh Binance week and
uh see you later again.
>> Thank you. Thank you.